<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>technology on Bits and Blocks</title>
    <link>https://www.corylogan.com/bits/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Bits and Blocks</description>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.55.5</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor> (Cory Logan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster> (Cory Logan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 05:35:47 UT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.corylogan.com/bits/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Serving Localhost to the Web with Reverse Ssh Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://www.corylogan.com/bits/bits/serving-localhost-to-the-web-with-reverse-ssh-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 13:12:03 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Cory Logan</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://www.corylogan.com/bits/bits/serving-localhost-to-the-web-with-reverse-ssh-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>Note: If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a server already, check my last tip.
This topic is always a little tricky, so, here&amp;rsquo;s the basic thing to know, as this is the most frequent use case.
Suppose you have a development rails server running on your local computer. You can access this server via curl http://localhost:3000. Which is to say, it&amp;rsquo;s running on your localhost, on port 3000. You want your client to see it, to give you feedback, but they&amp;rsquo;re nowhere near you, and you just want a quick way to show it to them.</description>
      <category domain="https://www.corylogan.com/categories/technology">Technology</category>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Note: If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a server already, check my last tip.
This topic is always a little tricky, so, here&amp;rsquo;s the basic thing to know, as this is the most frequent use case.
Suppose you have a development rails server running on your local computer. You can access this server via curl http://localhost:3000. Which is to say, it&amp;rsquo;s running on your localhost, on port 3000. You want your client to see it, to give you feedback, but they&amp;rsquo;re nowhere near you, and you just want a quick way to show it to them.
Fortunately for you, you know about ssh. You know that it will take you just a few seconds to set up a reverse tunnel through an intermediate server. Cake! Huh?
Things you&amp;rsquo;ll need, and their values in my example:
 Some kind of server on the web running sshd (yourserver.com) A local webserver accessible (0.0.0.0:3000)  ssh -NR 3333:localhost:3000 user@yourserver.com Now that the tunnel is running, you should be able to access your web server at http://yourserver.com:3333. You can of course change either of the ports. There are a few caveats, but this is it in the basic form.
Troubleshooting If that&amp;rsquo;s not working for you, chances are you need the GatewayPorts yes option added to the file /etc/ssh/sshd_config on the server. Go in there and add that line, then restart the ssh service. With ubuntu that&amp;rsquo;s just sudo service ssh restart.
Tips  You can run this in the background if you want by adding the -f flag. I prefer to run it in the foreground when I&amp;rsquo;m just using it for a moment, or troubleshooting as it&amp;rsquo;s easier to kill. If you run it in the background, and you just try to run it again on the same port, they will collide, and you will fail. Lower port numbers (lower than 1024) can&amp;rsquo;t be used unless you&amp;rsquo;re a super user on the system. Generally, it&amp;rsquo;s just easier to use a higher port number on the remote server. The -v flag will give you the full ssh output with authentication. This is another common source of problems. If you have a few dollars, and not much interest in the topic, check out ngrok, it&amp;rsquo;s a great tool that really takes most of the trouble out of it. It also means you don&amp;rsquo;t need to bring your own server! If you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to run your own server, this is the way to go.  ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Process Is Hogging My Port On Mac Os</title>
      <link>https://www.corylogan.com/bits/bits/what_process_is_hogging_my_port_on_mac_os/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 19:51:29 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Cory Logan</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://www.corylogan.com/bits/bits/what_process_is_hogging_my_port_on_mac_os/</guid>
      <description>Address already in use Damn. Did I leave a server running somewhere? Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;re not sure where you left a server running, or where something is running you never knew about. I&amp;rsquo;m finally writing this down, as I always have to look it up. I found this solution in a StackOverflow post.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to get all of the processes by what port they&amp;rsquo;re using.
sudo lsof -iTCP -sTCP:LISTEN -n -P As A Shell Function Looking at it, I realized I would never remember it, given how infrequently I need it.</description>
      <category domain="https://www.corylogan.com/categories/technology">Technology</category>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[ Address already in use Damn. Did I leave a server running somewhere? Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;re not sure where you left a server running, or where something is running you never knew about. I&amp;rsquo;m finally writing this down, as I always have to look it up. I found this solution in a StackOverflow post.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to get all of the processes by what port they&amp;rsquo;re using.
sudo lsof -iTCP -sTCP:LISTEN -n -P As A Shell Function Looking at it, I realized I would never remember it, given how infrequently I need it. So, I wrote a function. You should be able to pop this into your .bashrc or .zshrc, or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re using.
function whats_using { if [ -z $1 ]; then sudo lsof -iTCP -sTCP:LISTEN -n -P else sudo lsof -iTCP -sTCP:LISTEN -n -P | grep $1 fi } Now you can search for what&amp;rsquo;s using a port like so, or don&amp;rsquo;t specify a port number to return all results.
➜ whats_using 8181 com.docke 4082 cory 20u IPv4 0xa05b24c922aef1a1 0t0 TCP *:8181 (LISTEN) com.docke 4082 cory 21u IPv6 0xa05b24c91a710329 0t0 TCP [::1]:8181 (LISTEN)]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
